

Arnulfo Israel Ramos Magaña

Full Stack Developer

Contact Information

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/israel-ramos/ Phone: 3411362414

Profile

I been involved in several projects using many technologies, from java to C#, and on different environments and frameworks like Svelte, React/Redux, Express, NestJS with typescript and implementing IBM cloud technologies on those applications. My focus is to keep learning frontend, backend and cloud technologies and implement them on different projects in the future.

Technical Skills

Experienced		Basic/Intermediate
p		Knowledge
Javascript	REST	Java
TypeScript	Git	ASP.NET
Nodejs	HTML5	C#
NestJS	CSS	.NET Core
Svelte		AngularJS
Expressjs		Bootstrap
IBM Cloud Technologies		Webpack
React/Redux		JQuery

Work Experience

IBM – Full Stack Developer

Feb 2019 – Today

- I worked with IBM Cloud technologies in projects that raise cases from external parties and are evaluated for administrators. At the same time, I was involved in the development of the project using technologies like Svelte/Typescript for the frontend and NestJS for the backend with a connection to the IBM Cloud technologies.
- I oversaw the development of microservices with three other developers within several projects using IBM Cloud's Event Streams technologies that are built on kafka.

• I was involved on a project that uses React/Redux for the frontend and Expressjs for the backend. The project is use by employees to have information about the company and how they can address issues and concerns about almost anything that happen around them in the office, team or/and in general. Once was finished, I became the maintainer and developer lead of the application.

Tata Consultancy Services – Developer

Feb 2019 - Oct 2020

- My main responsibility was on the side of credit cards and loans of the client, making changes to the backend and the frontend using technologies like Java, their own implementation of JSP. Also made documentation and showcasing the changes to the stakeholders.
- I worked on internal projects that help managers and employees to make life easy inside the office, using technologies with HTML5, CSS, Javascript and Jquery.
- I was involved on the Onboarding team for new employees to show them the installation and have a close contact for any doubt they have about the company or process.
- I was also involved on the Learning and Development team. In that time, we organized sessions and events to all in office employees to learn new technologies and/or have knowledge transfer for one or more projects.

Unosquare – Software Engineer

Mar 2017 - Ago 2018

- I was part of the development and deployment of the main website of the company mostly using HTML5, JS, CSS3, jQuery, bootstrap and .NET with C#.
- I was involved on several open-source projects owned by Unosquare using different technologies and frameworks like Angular, Typescript, React and configurations with webpack, with unit-testing and end-to-end testing.
- I participate in projects using C# with .NET and .NET Core making important modifications and upgrades to the base API.

Unosquare - Internship

Sep 2016 - Mar 2017

• I was preparing and passed the certification test form Microsoft 480, 486 and 487.

Languages

Spanish – Mother Tongue

English - Intermediate

Education

Guadalajara University – Telematics Engineer

Jan 2013 – Dec 20